# Carlos Alberto de la Guardia Piedra

A dedicated and highly skilled Cybersecurity Analyst with a strong background in telecommunications systems and network management. Experienced in designing, implementing, and maintaining secure network infrastructures, I possess strong analytical and troubleshooting capabilities essential for identifying and mitigating cybersecurity threats. Committed to delivering exceptional service and staying abreast of the latest cybersecurity trends and technologies.



## **PERSONAL INFO**

EMAIL PHONE LINKEDIN

cdelaguardia1987@gmail.com +528110696724 https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlos-alberto-de-laquardia-piedra-b74556242/

## **WORK HISTORY**

## **IT Support Specialist and Help Desk**

[2022/10 - Present]

INFOGA, ESCOBEDO, NUEVO LEON

In August 2022 I moved to Mexico to study at the Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León. After a while, I started working at Infoga, an Internet and electronic security service provider, located in Escobedo, Nuevo León.

- · Provide remote and on-site support for laptops, PCs, printers, mobile devices, and other equipment. Provide
- technical support for software or hardware maintenance and installation.
- Diagnose and troubleshoot wireless network outages.
- · Installation and maintenance of CCTV systems.

## Specialist in Telematics (Network Management Group)

[2021/06 - 2022/07]

ETECSA, SANTA CLARA, CUBA

In June 2021, a change was made in the organizational structure of the ETECSA Company, so I became a Telematics Specialist in the Network Administration Group. In this new position, in addition to the functions I had previously, I have had to assume new ones:

- Perform the supervision of the technological sites in the specialty of Transmission.
- Participate in field tests for the introduction of new technologies and certify that they meet the requirements for operation. Participate in the
- Identification of vulnerabilities in the telecommunications network and propose actions to mitigate or eradicate them.
- · Proficient in the design, installation, and maintenance of telecommunications systems, including voice and data networks.

## **Specialist in Telematics (Operations Support Group)**

[2011/09 - 2021/05]

ETECSA, SANTA CLARA, CUBA

After completing the period of job training, I held the position of Telematics Specialist, attending the engineering of the Network. In this position I have served:

- Carrying out studies of the different performance indicators of the telecommunications network and proposing actions to optimize
  the physical and logical resources that compose it to improve these indicators.
- Managing the processes of acceptance and start-up of the investments made, according to the protocols and standards of the specialties
  of Switching, Transmission, Tele-traffic, Access, and Energy
- I have managed to carry out projects that have solved existing service needs in remote rural communities by optimizing the use of equipment.
- Design and implementation of the GPON network in the Cayo Santa María Tourist Pole
- Design, installation, and maintenance of telecommunications systems, including voice (NGN) and data networks.
- The Operation, Maintenance, and Homologation of Energy and Backup Systems for Telecommunications Equipment.
- Identification of vulnerabilities in the telecommunications network and propose actions to mitigate or eradicate them.
- · Measurement and analysis of radio signal propagation
- Installation, Operation, Maintenance, and Solution of Faults of Radio-link equipment, mainly from the manufacturers Huawei, Nokia, and Ericsson.
- Characteristics and types of Fiber Optics.
- · Installation of Fiber Optic Networks, complying with technical standards. Measurements for Fault Detection in Fiber Optic Networks.

•

## **EDUCATION**

Spanish

English

Telecommunications, Master's Degree in Electrical Science. [2022/08 - Present] UNIVERSIDAD AUTÓNOMA DE NUEVO LEÓN, SAN NICOLÁS DE LOS GARZA, NUEVO LEÓN, MÉXICO Telecommunications, Diploma in Network Administration [2017/09 - 2018/07]UNIVERSIDAD CENTRAL "MARTA ABREU" DE LAS VILLAS, SANTA CLARA, CUBA Telecommunications, Degree in Telecommunications and [2006/09 - 2011/07]**Electronics Engineering** UNIVERSIDAD CENTRAL "MARTA ABREU" DE LAS VILLAS, SANTA CLARA, CUBA **SKILLS** Cross-functional collaboration Self-learning Analysis and critical thinking Threat and vulnerability research and Security event monitoring and Logical and mathematical reasoning evaluation analysis Security information and event **Networking Tools and Protocols** Vulnerability scanning management (SIEM) Cybersecurity incident management and Security tool configuration and Security awareness training maintenance reporting Security policy development and Incident response and remediation Risk assessment and mitigation implementation **Endpoint security** Intrusion detection and prevention Network security Compliance and regulatory Access control and identity management frameworks SOFTWARE Wireshark Elastic Splunk MS Office Matlab Python SQL **LANGUAGES** 

## **COURSES**

SOC Analyst (HackTheBox)	[Present]	Introduction to Threat Hunting & Hunting With Elastic (HackThebox)	[03/2024]
Understanding Log Sources & Investigating with Splunk (HackThebox)	[03/2024]	Security Monitoring & SIEM Fundamentals (HackTheBox)	[03/2024]
Incident Handling Process (HackThebox)	[03/2024]	Intermediate Network Traffic Analysis (HackThebox)	[03/2024]
Windows Event Logs & Finding Evil (HackTheBox)	[01/2024]	Intro to Active Directory (HackThebox)	[01/2024]
Wireshark for Beginners: Capture Packets (Coursera Project Network)	[01/2024]	Google Cybersecurity Specialization (Coursera)	[12/2023]
Intro to Network Traffic Analysis (HackThebox)	[12/2023]	Microsoft Windows Defender and Firewall for Beginners (Coursera Project Network)	[12/2023]
Mastercard - Cybersecurity Job Simulation (Forage)	[12/2023]	English for TI 1 by Cisco	[09/2023]
Data Fundamentals by IBM	[05/2023]	Python Essencials 1 and 2 by Cisco	[01/2023]
Huawei WLAN. Planning and Design with SVA 3200	[09/2017]	Huawei OptiX RTN-905 Equipment Operation and Maintenance Course	[06/2017]
WLL Multigain Wireless Innowave ECI Telecom System. Operation and Maintenance	[11/2015	DSLAM ALCATEL ISAM7302, 7330-735x. Management System 5520 AMS	[04/2015]
GPON - ZTE system. Basic Course for Network Engineering	[02/2015]	SDH-OSN Network Course (1500B, 2500, 3500, 7500)	[01/2015]
TCP/IP network architecture. WAN Networks	[09/2014]	Basic Course of IP/MPLS Networks	[03/2013]